Finding Aid for Sheryl M. Szady papers, 1984-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Sheryl M. Szady papers
1984-2010
1997-2007
Szady, Sheryl Marie.
2014121 Aa2 Ac
Sheryl M. Szady is a University of Michigan alumna and employee who played an integral role in the evolution of women's athletics at the university. The collection includes meeting minutes, correspondence and other materials from her work with numerous university affiliated organizations including the Friends of the Michigan League, the Kinesiology Alumni Society, and Letterwinners M Club, as well as Interlochen Center for the Arts in Interlochen, Michigan.
5 linear feet
1 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The papers of Sheryl Szady (donor no. 7769 ) were received in multiple accessions in 2010.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Sheryl M. Szady received her B.S. in Physical Education (1974), M.S. (1975), and Ph.D. (1987) from the University of Michigan. Her Ph.D. dissertation was entitled, "The History of Intercollegiate Athletics for Women at the University of Michigan," and is available through the University of Michigan's Deep Blue digital repository. While attending Michigan as an undergraduate, Szady played field hockey, volleyball, and basketball. When she began playing, all women's sports at the University of Michigan were club sports. As co-president of the Michigan Sports Club Federation (MSCF), Szady worked with fellow students and faculty to establish a varsity intercollegiate athletic program for women. She sat on the Committee to Study Intercollegiate Athletics for women, sometimes referred to as the Burns Committee. The committee's reports led to the creation of six varsity women's sports for the 1973-1974 season. Additionally, Szady helped secure the 'block M' award for the University of Michigan's women athletes in 1975.
Szady worked for the University of Michigan throughout her career, retiring in 2012 from her position as Director, Research and Marketing Data in the Office of Development. During her tenure, she was active on the board of numerous organizations, including: M Women, Letterwinners M Club (M Club), Friends of the Michigan League, Kinesiology Alumni Society, and the Interlochen Center for the Arts.
Szady participated in Interlochen Center for the Arts' Interlochen Arts Camp (1971-1984), and was on the Interlochen Arts Academy faculty (1975-1982) teaching physical and health education. She is a member and past president of the Interlochen Alumni Organization and a former ex-officio member of ICA's Board of Trustees.
The Sheryl Szady papers include meeting minutes, correspondence and other materials from her work with numerous university affiliated organizations and Interlochen Center for the Arts. The papers date from 1984-2010, with the bulk of documentation from 1997-2007. The collection is divided into two subgroups: University of Michigan and Interlochen Center for the Arts.
Subjects:
College sports.; Interlochen Center for the Arts.; "M" Club (University of Michigan); Michigan League.; Physical education and training.; Physical education for women--Michigan.; Szady, Sheryl Marie.; Universities and colleges--Alumni and alumnae--Michigan.; University of Michigan. Division of Kinesiology.
- University of Michigan
  The Sheryl Szady papers include meeting minutes, correspondence and other materials from her work with numerous university affiliated organizations and Interlochen Center for the Arts. The papers date from 1984-2010, with the bulk of documentation from 1997-2007. The collection is divided into two subgroups: University of Michigan and Interlochen Center for the Arts.
  - Alumni Research Conferences, 1989-2000
    The Alumni Research Conferences, 1989-2000, series contains agendas, meeting and her presentation materials for two conferences, the AIR Institute Conference (1989-1990) and BSR Conference (1989-2000), arranged chronologically. These conferences focused on the collection and utilization of alumni research data.
    - AIR Institute Conference, 1989-1990; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - BSR Conference, 1989-2000 (Box 1)
  - UM Alumni Census, 1986
    The UM Alumni Census, 1986, contains the official alumni census report, including the census survey, findings, strategic planning and evaluation. The census was conducted to get updated information on alumni and gather data for use in enhancing fund solicitation during the Campaign for Michigan.
    - UM Alumni Census and Analysis, 1986; 10 folders (Box 1)
  - Michigan League, 1995-2009
    The Michigan League, 1995-2009, series is divided into three subseries: Friends of the Michigan League Board, 1995-2009; Board of Governors, 2002-2009; Miscellaneous, 2003-2009. The first subseries, arranged chronologically, primarily contains meeting agendas, minutes, and supplemental material; by-laws, fundraising materials; newsletters; and other miscellaneous records for the Friends of the Michigan League. The Board of Governors subseries, arranged chronologically, primarily contains meeting agendas, minutes, supplemental material, and the Member Manual for the Michigan League Board of Governors. The Miscellaneous subseries consists primarily of printed materials and records pertaining to the University Unions as a whole.
    - Friends of the Michigan League Board, 1995-2009
      - Agendas and Minutes, 1999-2009; 3 folders (Box 1)
      - By-Laws and Mission Statement, undated-2008 (Box 1)
      - Business Correspondence, 2000-2009 (Box 1)
      - Development Committee, 2000-2004 (Box 1)
      - Fundraising, 1999-2009 (Box 1)
      - Fundraising Campaign, 2003-2009 (Box 1)
      - Member Lists, 1999-2009 (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
      - Newsletter, 1999-2009 (Box 1)
      - Stained Glass Census, 1995-2005 (Box 1)
    - Board of Governors, 2002-2009
      - Agendas, 2002-2008; 4 folders (Box 1)
      - Executive Committee, 2005-2006 (Box 1)
      - Friends of the Michigan League and Board of Governors joint meeting, 2006-2007 (Box 1)
      - Member Manual, circa, 2004-2005; 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Minutes, 2002-2008 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Subseries, 2003-2009
      - Miscellaneous, 2003-2006 (Box 1)
      - Printed Materials, undated (Box 1)
      - University Unions, 2005-2009 (Box 1)
  - Kinesiology Alumni Society, 1994-2006
    The Kinesiology Alumni Society, 1994-2006, series, arranged chronologically, consists of meeting agendas, minutes, and supplemental material; correspondence; and miscellaneous materials.
    - Board Meetings, 1997-2006; 17 folders (Box 2)
    - Board Materials, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 2)
    - Hartwig Collegiate Scholarship Fund, 2000-2001 (Box 2)
    - Memoranda, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1994-2005 (Box 2)
    - Research and Development, 1999 (Box 2)
  - M Club (Letterwinners M Club), 2006-2010
    The M Club, 2006-2010, series, arranged chronologically, includes meeting agendas, minutes and supplemental materials for the Letterwinners M Club board and business meetings; correspondence; publications and other materials pertaining to M Club.
    - Board Meetings, 2006-2007; 10 folders (Box 2)
    - Business Meetings, 2007-2010; 25 folders (Box 2)
    - Business Correspondence, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Email Correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box 2)
    - Hall of Honor Nominations, 2006-2007 (Box 2)
    - M Club and Alumni Association Conference Call, 2009 (Box 2)
    - Michigan Booster Groups Annual Meetings, 2006-2009; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Publications -- Flyers, 2008-2009 (Box 2)
    - Publications -- M News Newsletter, 2007-2008 (Box 2)
    - Reports, 2009 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous UM Athletics, 1984-2009
    The Miscellaneous UM Athletics, 1984-2009, series, arranged chronologically, consists of materials from various University of Michigan organizations, departments, and facilities related to athletics, including: The Central Campus Recreation Building, Paul Robeson Research Center (affiliated with the Department of Kinesiology), Recreational Sports, Sports Institute, UM Athletic Department, UM Corner Club (field hockey), Victors Club, and Victory Hoops Club (basketball).
    - Central Campus Recreation Building (CCRB), 1984-1989 (Box 2)
    - Paul Robeson Research Center, 1998-1999 (Box 2)
    - Recreational Sports, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
    - Sports Institute, 1997-1999 (Box 2)
    - UM Athletic Department, 2002-2003 (Box 2)
    - UM Corner Club, ca. 1997-, circa 2005 (Box 2)
    - Victors Club, 1998-2009 (Box 2)
    - Victory Hoops Club, 2000-2008 (Box 2)
- Interlochen Center for the Arts
  The Interlochen Center for the Arts subgroup is divided into four series: General, Interlochen Alumni Organization, Board of Trustees, and Printed Materials.
  - General, 1997-2007
    The General, 1997-2007, series contains materials pertaining to Interlochen Center for the Arts programs which are not directly related to the Board of Trustees or the Interlochen Alumni Organization. This includes: 75th Anniversary materials, By-Laws, Commencement ceremony invitations and programs, fundraising, Interlochen Arts Camp, Interlochen Pathfinder School, Interlochen Public Radio, seventh ICA president Jeffrey Kimpton, Correspondence, Press and Press Releases, materials related to the 2003-2004 restructure, and miscellaneous other items.
    - 75th Anniversary, 2002-2003 (Box 3)
    - By-Laws, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Commencement ceremonies, 2001-2004 (Box 3)
    - Fundraising, 2003-2006 (Box 3)
    - Interlochen Arts Camp, 1997-2004 (Box 3)
    - Interlochen Pathfinder School, 2001; 2007 (Box 3)
    - Interlochen Public Radio, ca. 2000-, circa 2001 (Box 3)
    - Jeffrey Kimpton, May 2003 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous, ca. 1998-, circa 2006 (Box 3)
    - Personal Correspondence, 2001-2007 (Box 3)
    - Press, 2000-2006 (Box 3)
    - Press Releases, 2001-2002 (Box 3)
    - Restructure, 2003-2004 (Box 3)
  - Interlochen Alumni Organization, 1991-2009
    The Interlochen Alumni Organization, 1991-2009, series consists of materials related to Alumni events, weekends, retreats, and reunions; IAO Board meeting agendas, supplemental materials, and minutes; member lists, projects, and By-Laws; and correspondence, including a debate on election procedure.
    - Alumni Events, 2002-2003 (Box 3)
    - Alumni Weekend 2002, 2005, 2009 (Bulk 2002) (Box 3)
    - Board Meetings, 1998-2009; 23 folders (Box 3)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 2000-2008 (Box 3)
    - Board Members, 1999-2006 (Box 3)
    - Board Projects, 1992-1994 (Box 3)
    - Business Correspondence, 1997-2007 (Box 3)
    - By-Laws, 1991-? (Box 3)
    - By-Laws; Role of IAO, April-July 2001 (Box 3)
    - Elections, 2002-2003 (Box 3)
    - Executive Committee Retreat, December 1997 (Box 3)
    - Reunions, 2000-2007 (Box 3)
    - Volleyball Reunion, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Board of Trustees, 1991-2008
    The Board of Trustees, 1991-2008, series consists of annual reports; meeting agendas, supplemental materials and minutes; member lists; correspondence; committees, including the Investment committee; the Institute for Education and the Arts; and ICA strategic plans.
    - Board Meetings, 2000-2004; 15 folders (Box 4)
    - Annual Report, 2000 (Box 5)
    - Annual Report, 2001 (Box 5)
    - Annual Report, 2003 (Box 5)
    - Annual Report, 2004 (Box 5)
    - Annual Report, 2008 (Box 5)
    - Board Members, 1999-2004 (Box 5)
    - Brand and Communications Audit, 2004 (Folder AC)
    - Business Correspondence, 2000-2004 (Box 5)
    - Committees, 2000-2004 (Box 5)
    - Institute for Education and the Arts, 2002 (Box 5)
    - Investment Committee, 2001-2003 (Box 5)
    - Meeting Minutes, 2000-2004 (Box 5)
    - Strategic Plans, 1991-2004 (Box 5)
  - Printed Materials, 2000-2009; undated
    The Printed Materials, 2000-2009, series consists of brochures, flyers, programs and miscellaneous other materials printed by ICA. This series is organized by the ICA program in the materials, including: Arts Festival, fundraising, Interlochen Arts Academy, Interlochen Arts Camp, the presidential newsletter Interlochen Briefing, Interlochen Center for the Arts, Interlochen College of Creative Arts, Interlochen Pathfinder School, reunion programs, miscellaneous invitations, miscellaneous programs, and miscellaneous other printed items.
    - Arts Festival, 2001-2009 (Box 5)
    - Fundraising, 2000-2006; undated (Box 5)
    - Interlochen Arts Academy, 2001-2006; undated (Box 5)
    - Interlochen Arts Camp, 2000-2008; undated (Box 5)
    - "Interlochen Briefing", 2004-2006 (Box 5)
    - Interlochen Center for the Arts, 2000-2008; undated (Box 5)
    - Interlochen College of Creative Arts, 2005-2009 (Box 5)
    - Interlochen Pathfinder School, 2000-2005; undated (Box 5)
    - Invitations, 2000-2009; undated (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 2001-2006; undated (Box 5)
    - Programs, 2000-2008 (Box 5)
    - Reunion Programs, 2000-2009 (Box 5)
Related Material
Sheryl Szady has donated additional materials to the Bentley Historical Library that can be found in other collections. Researchers interested in Szady's other materials (most notably those pertaining to women's athletics and Interlochen Center for the Arts) should search for Sheryl Szady across all finding aids.
Researchers interested in women's athletics at the University of Michigan may want to consult the Bentley Library's exhibit, "A Sporting Chance: Women's Athletics at the University of Michigan" (http://bentley.umich.edu/exhibits/womensathletics/) as well as the following collections containing materials donated by Sheryl Szady:
M Women Publications
Michigan Women's Athletic Association of the University of Michigan records
Marie D. Hartwig papers
Researchers interested in materials related to the Interlochen Center for the Arts in Interlochen, MI should consult the Bentley Historical Library's following collection:
Interlochen Center for the Arts records